The Institution
To the barricades!
Herr von Wagner!
Herr Uthoff!
How do you get past our barricades?
I took the lift
That's what happens when your barricade has to have disabled access
Herr Timoschenko.
- I... I ...
- What exactly are you doing here?
What are you doing here?
What exactly are you doing here, paralympics or something?
7 days 7 pigtails, or what?
What does it look like?  We're having a revolution!
Stop that, you're just associating yourself with the common people
Which has become a recurring theme in uprisings
Every time
You think you...
Tell me... why is there Cyrillic on that banner?
Solidarity with the Ukraine!
It's now time to instill the fire of revolution into the hearts of our citizens, too,
and to sweep away these corrupt elitists!
And you're doing that by performing a musical of Les Miserables?
You see, merely setting the rigid conditions
to your own melody is enough to make them dance
Lovely, Andrew Lloyd Webber?
Karl Marx
- And who are these people?
- All battle-ready citizens, let me introduce
- Comrade Pussy
- I'm with you!
Comrade Bussy
Busse!
Who's the guy over there on the right?
We prefer not to know the exact details
but he found us the weapons
Let's go
Tell me, have you forgotten who we are?
- No, we are the Occupiers of the Institution
- That's right!
The Action of Fanatical Democrats, for short, the AF...
We should stick to the longer version
We are here to objectively explain political factors
Let me guess, he's in charge of the positive atmosphere?
Herr Uthoff, you won't manage to choke our revolutionary fire this time!
Isn't that right, men?
Tell me, do you really believe
that people these days trust amateurs like you with something as important as revolution?
We're not amateurs, we're doing this as in a voluntary capacity,
okay, but we're not...
- Voluntary?
Unpaid?
That's not what you said earlier
What did he say?
We're walking out
It's a miracle!  I'm walking!
Herr von Wagner, today revolutions in the Ukraine are organised by professionals
Here, by him, for example
Yeah, Witali Klitschko, now that's a real revolutionary!
Have you ever heard him speaking without notes?
Don't be unfair, he's spent his entire life wearing a mouthgard
I don't think he can even speak Ukrainian properly, but he wants to be president there
You know, I'd be happier if I didn't understand every word
our president says
Forget it
Forget this puppet from the Konrad Adenauer Foundation
No, the real pro is on his right, John McCain,
former US presidential candidate, here in December on the Maidan
McCain, what's he doing there, selling fries?
The man's been working with his foundation for a long time
at giving the Ukranians a taste for a market-compliant democracy
- Yeah yeah, and then they have to suck...
- Huh?
at giving the Ukranians a taste for a market-compliant democracy
- Yeah yeah, and then they have to suck...
- Huh?
Yep, succumb to the West
The Americans have invested
a total of $5 billion into the coup in the Ukraine
- Yeah, says Putin
- No, Victoria Nuland
- Fuck you
Look, there she was on the Maidan in December,
the acting US Foreign Secretary
Look at that, the Americans as the breadgivers
of Ukrainian Revolution
Imagine that the other way round
Putin goes to the Occupy Wall Street demonstrators, gives out solyanka,
millions of dollars, then sits down and says, "Mr. President,
tear down this Wall Street."
OK, now we've
OK, now we've established neatly that the Americans are the bad guys,
but the Russians can attack a sovereign country just like that?
Now you'll say "They were just having a carnival party,
Shrove Monday in Crimea."
You know, with military uniforms from a party store
Puten touches the Ukraine from behind, on the shoulder...
You know what I'll tell you?
What the Russians did was against the law of nations
The American Foreign Secretary said it beautifully,
he said, "No country should invade another under false pretenses,
to further its own interests."
Hey, would you mind repeating that sentence?
Yes of course.  "No country should invade another
under false pretenses, to..."
Those are Sadam's weapons
The language of diplomacy, hm?  Easily tainted in the time of propaganda
When the needle points to "War", it's best to listen the enemy's broadcasts
So, everything the Russian intelligence happens to reveal
Rolling off the imperial tongue,
Western leaders prattle on about
how they see the future in the Ukraine.
Or who really did shoot on the Maidan.
The German media don't normally pick up on that
because they're too busy with their shortwave radios,
looking for stories which confirm
their views of the evil Putin
And so,
Hitler comparisons go wild
like crocusses in a pile of dogpoo
It's true of all Nazi comparisons that not everything lame
is Joseph Goebbels
However it goes without saying that Frank Steinmeier,
our new Foreign Affairs Authority,
is the best Foreign Affairs Minister since...
our last one
Steinmeier, a four,
four-star diplomat, at the Munich Security Conference,
commanded the democratically elected
Ukrainian President to kindly accept
all demands of the Maidan demonstrators
Well, that's a tradition in our country
Every protest movement we can start is accepted here
That heats up the conflict and is good for our arms export
Embarrassing really, for years, German foreign affairs have suffered
from premature escalation
But, what an effect our Minister of Foreign Affairs Frank-and-Stein has
Hmm?
They endure months
in the bitter cold, at some point shots are fired, blood flows, but only
when the danger menaces that Steinmeier could hold a speech,
does everyone sit down at the negotiation table and sign
Frank Maier sign... Frank-Walter Steinmeier signed
the contract too
Well, the man signs
everything
I don't even want to know how many magazine subscriptions he has
So he...
So he enthusiastically shakes the hands of the Nazis from the Swoboda party
and wonders why one hour later, these shady characters
break the contract
I think this is a matter for the Guiness Book of Records:
Five weeks
after the reorientation of German Foreign Affairs,
Nazis enter the Ukranian government
Never before could we observe so neatly
how it looks when the West
exploits a new country as a globalised
shopping mall
The International Monetary Fund
The IMF
offered Janukowytsch
several billion but only under the condition that he
raise the gas prices by 40%, inline with the market
And even a greedy moron like him couldn't accept that
And soon,
the international PR was running at full speed
Let's not get confused, this is not a conspiracy theory
this is conspiracy reality
The demonstrators freeze their arses of on the Maidan, and what
will they get out of it?
Higher gas prices
My dear Ukranians, those are the additional expenses of freedom
Actually, I wanted to defend Putin here
That the man is also allowed to have interests
That you can flip out when NATO, despite their promises,
are always cozying up from behind
But then I saw that his pal, the flawless Gerhard Schröder,
also defended him
with the splendid point that he would have also loved to break the law of nations
by bombing Serbia
and so we shouldn't point the finger now
Of course Schröder always showed the law of nations
his middle finger
And now
And now I am forced to change my opinion, because if history
has taught us one thing,
it's that when Gerhard Schröder thinks something is right, it can't be
more wrong
And that's why...
Excuse me, I am right in the middle of my solo
Oh, forgive me, Herr Uthoff, of course we all find it excellent
that you're sculpting the satirical stucco
onto the bourgeois ceiling of the circumstances
You don't sculpt stucco
You see, that's exactly what I mean.  No more of these lofty word landscapes
We want to finally see some heads roll!  Huh?
- Yes!
You see, that's exactly what I mean.  No more of these lofty word landscapes
We want to finally see some heads roll!  Huh?
- Yes!
Why not?  We have a guillotine here.
Oh oh, I faint at the sight of blood
Oh, don't worry about that
We have one for the Society of Humane Decaptiation
So
Now I'd like to make a few suggestions.
Well, who shall it be?
Janukowytsch, Janukowytsch!
Yes, what is he accused of?
- Um, he opressed his people...
- Yes!
Yes, what is he accused of?
- Um, he opressed his people...
- Yes!
Yes but he was elected by this people
Ah, the OECD said that too, but...
Come on, when you just eliminate any democratically
elected representative whose voters don't like him,
Hessen would have to vote yet again
Wulf, Wulf, Wulf, Wulf! [politician, allegedly bribed]
- What are the charges?
- He's a corrupt oligarch with a wonderful villa
But he was just acquitted
- But he did leave us with Gauk
- Gauk!  Gauk!
But why?
Um, well, Gauk declared himself guilty in Greece
- Morally but not legally
- And why is that?
Um, well, Gauk declared himself guilty in Greece
- Morally but not legally
- And why is that?
That was cheaper
Listen,
could you please
just decide?
- Blüm!  Blüm!  Norbert Blüm!
- What?
Please forgive me, but that was a cabarett reflex
from the 80s
- Then let's behead Friedrich!
- Yes!
But what should the charges be?
He never used his head
Crap.  Then Merkel maybe?
Merkel, Merkel, Merkel!
That is your first good idea, but
but, but, but why?
- Hey, what has she done these days?
- I'd also like to know!  What's actually
her full-time job?
Maybe Gabriel?
Gabriel!  Gabriel!  [head of the SPD]
Oh, come on, he wouldn't even fit in the guillotine
Then we'll use the electric chair
Yes, with wind power!
Wait, the major electrical grid's not even finished yet
Because of Seehofer!
- Seehofer!  Seehofer!
Wait, the major electrical grid's not even finished yet
Because of Seehofer!
- Seehofer!  Seehofer!
Wait, you couldn't get Seehofer on the guillotine
He turns so quickly, I'd end up just cutting his toenails
Ah!
The shame of the SPD!
Bowereit?
He's in the SPD?
I was thinking more of the Edathy
Edati!  Edati!  [found in possession of child pornography]
Theoretically I agree with you, but legally I don't think
we could pin anything on him
Hedge lawyer!
Paragraph screwer!
Maxi Uthoff is homosexual!  Homosexual, homosexual!
Now I have an idea for you, what about
Uli Hoeneß?  [former football player, evaded €28.5m in taxes]
No, the man has achieved so much!
And anyway, he already executed himself on the first day of the trail
That doesn't matter, then we'll behead him again,
the Bavarian...
- Wait, buy why?
That doesn't matter, then we'll behead him again,
the Bavarian...
- Wait, buy why?
Because it's his fault that the national league
has become so boring
- Yes!  Exactly!
We'll buy him!  Uli, Uli!
Wait, people, we can't even afford him!
€27m and rising daily!
Yes, lynch justice
So refreshing
I feel like 68
even though I'm now over 70
I want to say I think it's fantastic to be 70
and still
there at all
100 years ago that wouldn't have been conceivable, 100 years ago
the life expentancy of the average person was 55
And now, on average, we're at 86
On average!  There's still breathing room!
Old people have become
much less perischable
There are old people who are fitter than their chilren!
I can tell you, we have retirement homes in Germany
where parent-teacher interviews take place
Moving into a retirement home is of course the second most unmistakable sign
that you're getting old
The most unmistakable sign is however
putting a rubber mat with suction caps
in the shower
My doctor tells me you can medically establish
someone's biological age like this
So when you put a rubber mat with suction caps in the shower,
you're 70
When you place it with the suction caps
facing upwards,
you're 80
You're 90 when walk through the house with the suction caps sticking to your feet
and yell, "Mummy, these new slippers don't fit!"
But that only happens to people in retirement homes
They're not active anymore, they think all day about death, please
When you're over 70 like me
death's not even standing at the door yet
But he is looking for a parking space
And then it's nice for all the people who live in a pedestrian zone
The best way to avoid death is the way to the doctor
Everyone is running there
I'm telling you, after 70 people get felt up more often by their doctor
than by their own partner
And then they loll about in the waiting room from dawn 'till dusk
Always examinations
and checkups...  Checkups are a topic in themselves, aren't they?
My circle of friends consists of 8 people, in the last week,
7 had a checkup, one for gut, two for prostate,
two for breast cancer and two for uterus
And those were all men
No one knows
Not one of them knows
whether all of these checkups actually make a difference
That's why old people are readily persuaded
to have pointless, completely unnecessary operations
That leads however to overworked doctors
and for this reason it often happens that
something
is left behind in recently operated patients
Sometimes some pincers,
sometimes a swab,
sometimes a clamp
Now in Rheinland,
they operated on Reiner Galmund
Since then they've lost a small, Korean
operating theatre nurse
I'm not going the the doctor anymore!
Herr Bosse!
Does this ring a bell?
Not another birthday!
No, look at this!
Oh, my pension!  That thing on the right!
You must have got a letter as well
Yes, we did
Do you know what it was?
Information about my pension scheme.  And what did it say?
My pension is dead
And someone killed it.  You don't by any chance know who that could have been?
Blüm!  Blüm!  Norbert Blüm!
I have to see the doctor sometime about that
Blüm didn't have any motive
But there is one suspect
The Old Guy: Pension Murder
Herr Bosse, why did you kill the young man's pension?
That was more like euthanasia
Herr Busse
Bild am Sonntag, Süddeutsche Zeitung, Fokus, everyone agrees
The old people have killed the pensions, you are part of the old people, do you deny this?
If you confess, we'll let you live out your least years in peace
Well they don't belong to me anyway, I'm a public health patient
- And you're always getting older
- Yes, although you know that his makes the pensions inaffordable
Well they don't belong to me anyway, I'm a public health patient
- And you're always getting older
- Yes, although you know that his makes the pensions inaffordable
Herr Bosse, why are there so many of you and so few of us?
Sorry, but this is daytime television
Don't distract us from our opinion with facts
So, where were you 8 years ago, let's say at 2pm?
Retired
Aha, very suspicious
Was he familiar with this ship?
That is the Aila, you were seen several times on board
Yes, I started working again there
To supplement... my pension...
Are there witnesses to this?
Ah, that's difficult
Some aren't alive anymore, and some thought I was Rudi Carell
Herr Bosse, did you vote in 2013?
- Yes of course
- Ah ha ha
In this election, one third of the voters
- Yes of course
- Ah ha ha
In this election, one third of the voters
were over 60
Did your generation not have a disproportionately large influence on this election?
How can I help it if the young people don't vote?
Is it not true
that the government would like to give you your pension scheme
as a thank you for your vote?
You don't mean that was a retrospective bribe
something like the morning after pill?
Now I'm really awake
Why am I sitting on the defendant's bench?
You!  How many children have you brought into the world?
That's irrelevant
- One
- One, hah!
At 36?
- One
- One, hah!
At 36?
You must have partied hard, huh?
And you?
What did you pay into the retirement fund?
Nothing!  Not a cent!  He's a lawyer and because of this Law Society he gets
this extra provision, that's...
Now don't distract us from the facts, Interpol has calculated
Your pension "present" costs us about ̛€160 billion
- Yes, but only when
you make a projection based on the next 15 years
Great, but it's still the young people who pay
No, it's paid by all contributors
from 18 to 65
- So it's paid by all workers
No, the pensioners pay as well, because they receive a lower annuity rate
from 18 to 65
- So it's paid by all workers
No, the pensioners pay as well, because they receive a lower annuity rate
OK, now tell me, where exactly are we being screwed over?
I don't know, um, maybe...
Do you still need me here?
You!
You will stay here until you are guilty
Stop!  We need to admit something
We only simulating this inter-generational conflict
Just because it's so fun, look at the old wreck standing opposite
Jochen Busse
And it
You see, we actually like one another a lot
And this whole "war of the generations" is just a media concoction
I know it's hard to step down from an opinion just because the facts don't fit
But it's
You see, I also find it hard to dismiss the inter-generational conflict
Especially when I'm waiting in front of a pedestrian crossing
You know
And some pensioner, like a 56k modem,
shuffles across the street
And then the little Fokus reporter sitting on my shoulder says "Do it...
for the pension..."
I don't do it, of course
Normally
No, really, but I should really do it
Because of the wage deductions
Everyone told me, end of the 80s it started, oh God, the wage deductions
As a teenager I was more afraid of rising wage deductions than of an
atomic war
It was beaten into us: the old people are living much too long
not for free
End of the 80s, one of the most famous films was what?
"Die Hard"
The plot was obvious:
When the pension fund contributions rise,
the wage dedictions will rise and explode and all your jobs will be
vaporised, yippee-yi-yay, Schweinebacken
But just before the pensioners could roll over us
politics discovered this here:
The Pension Formula
Look at this, does anyone want to solve this?
Correct, the answer is zero, absolutely correct
And why?  That's because of all these factors here,
these "moderating factors".
With this, politics have decreased pensions by let's say 25%
Did you hear the uproar in the population?
No, that's why they're called "moderating factors"
Ladies and gentlemen, that, that was the, politics and everyone have
That was, I believe, the biggest pension decrease
in German history
Why did they do it?
Out of fear
Of demographic change
"Demographic change" - that's what people always said
Less and less young people have to feed more and more old people
The numbers were definite, the predictions were obvious
The young people, so, the number is halved,
the number of pensioners triples
Disaster
The beauty of the disaster is
it's already happened
from 1900 up to the year 2000
From 1900 up to the year 2000, the number of young people doubled
and the number of pensioners tripled
And what did we do during that time?
Expanded out welfare systems
And
Out standard of living has improved
You'll ask me "How is this possible?
Germany's economic strength!"
I'll show you quickly: This is
aproximately the economic strength of Germany in the year 1950
So, those were the golden days.
From this cake, we only had to give
14% to the pensioners
Today, we have to give more than 30%
to the pensioners
That would be a problem
If we think that the cake has stayed the same size
It doesn't, the cake has, thanks to modern technology
and my lovely assistant
That is the proportion, ladies and gentleman!
Thank you very much
That, ladies and gentlemen, is the cake that we can share
And still, we say we should make our belts a little tighter
And now you rightly say
"Wait, if there's so much cake there to share, what's with my pension?"
A small story
Imagine an employer
who invites every one to his birthday party every year, and every year
he bakes a larger cake
You come each year and get a smaller piece than last year
And you ask him why?
And he says, "Because otherwise we would all starve,"
and he points to an old man in the corner, whose piece of cake you immediately take
because you're afraid to starve
And because you're so caught up in a generation conflict with these old people in the corner,
you never find time to wonder who, in the story,
got the biggest part of the cake
The employer
But you're not allowed to say that too loudly
Otherwise someone will come and says "Shhhhh,
when the cake speaks,
the crumbs are silent."
We can come in?  Everyone gone?
No one's left?  That's good.
Sorry that I'm secretly creeping into the show
But I really have to warn you
That it's very, very dangerous, what the Herr von Wagner just did with you
He tried to take away your fear
Fear of the demographical disaster
But fear, dear people
Fear is the biggest motivator to make something of yourself
Fear in your throat, hah?  It spurs you on, gives you the signal,
"People, get going, always bite off more than you can chew,
shove the others out of the way and screw the future
If you want to catch lots of fish,
has to fish with dynamite, huh?
Never give up, a German chicken fights until the barbeque!"
That is the positive side of fear
Yes sir!
You've noticed?
I'm Germany's first neoliberal caberettist
That's why I had to smuggle myself into the Insitution in this cake
To get myself access to this gang of left-wing weirdos,
who think you need to get to the bottom of everything
The pension formula, he's explaining to you?
Has he gone crazy?  That's much to complicated
You shouldn't even try to understand that
I tell you too much knowledge is also a hindrance
Yeah, when you know too much, you end up spending 6 weeks
in an airport in Moscow, really not good
Although
Excuse me
To be entirely honest, Snowden, the guy, also completely overrated,
What he knows he also only got from the Internet, but...
No, don't always question everything
Just let other people solve your problems
Just trust our government for once, Merkel will handle it
I have complete trust in her
Really, how issues drip off her
She's just acting, right?
There aren't really any problems, ah?
Press conference, masterful statement from her
And after that she departs
with publicists, advisors and everyone in her wake
And then she always says something or other to them, you never hear it though
And that's what I find really cool, when she says,
"Yes, that's our position in the NSA affair"
And then she always stamps away like that
And I always imagine her saying to Seibert,
"Hey Stefan, wanna play Playstation?"
Really, honestly!
When I see that, man, I know that she'll solve all your problems
And it's good like that
I mean, you already have enough to do fighting your own challenges
Look what's expected from you
The whole day long, you try,
with limited resources, to keep several things moving simulteneously
and to control them somehow with anticipatory actions
And that's the problem with complex challenges like this one here, that it...
Thank you very much
Yes, the problem
with complex challenges is that there are always multiple ways to solve them
And when there are multiple solutions, you have to constantly decide
when you need to step in, when to let go again, to keep everything
moving simulaneously
That means, you're completely overwhelmed already
I mean, work is a series of ups and downs anyway
but again and again
the question circles your head, "Are you the master
of all these processes,
or are they just being followed through,
one after the another?
of all these processes,
or are they just being followed through,
one after the another?
But of course also
because you get bogged down in the details in this whole
flood of information
You have the feeling you're not getting anywhere
Just turning around your own axis
Also because when implementing new processes you're often much too
clumsy
You're much too clumsy
Then of course mistake are made
You behave much too clumsily
Of course, to this is added a massive amount of social pressure
I mean, how often do you find yourself in some power political banter, yeah?
Sometimes also with your own boss, behind whose back
you always think,
"Man, does he really use both halves of his brain?"
How can he...
Permanent chaos in this place
The phone ringing constantly
You're happy when you can keep one hand on the keyboard, for at least
a little
research on the Internet
Everything is getting more and more hectic, faster, crazier
And you want to think critically?
I'll tell you one thing:
Just stay away
Herr Wopp!
How did you get in here?
I'm here to expand my customer base
The Trojan Cake, clever
We didn't occupy this show so men could play with their balls
I don't care about that
Tell me, have you ever thought about your future?
Retirement plan?
You won't get a cent of pension for your occupation here
Yeah, short thoughts lead to long faces
It's a hard case
But I have something for you
A private pension
What about the company pension?
The company pension was part of the new coalition
And you are lucky enough to he one of the first, come here
How should we do this?
Maybe a little role play?
Listen: Compay pension, private pension...
Herr Sieber, I think,
in our little game,
you can be the saver
What makes you think of that?
Just a guess
And Herr von Wagner,
you're the state
That's right, I'm Mummy
And Herr Bosse is a pensioner
There must be something different about me
But Herr Bosse, you're not a normal pensioner, you're Herr Sieber in 50 years' time
My God, I really haven't aged well
No surprise considering what I had to work with
- Who am I then?
- Herr Uthoff,
you are the company
and have just started offering a company pension
Does that cost something?
No no, not a cent!
You just allow me
to set up contracts with your employees
Because the boss has approved it,
it looks more professional, OK?
Shall we start, Herr Sieber?
How much would you like to put aside?
Knowing you, I'd say
maximum contribution, right?
Terrible cliché, that
Let's do it
4% of your salary, every month, over 40 years!
And here comes the clincher:
The state will help you
Thanks to Mummy, you'll pay less taxes
and less social welfare
Herr Sieber, do you feel poorly?
A private pension plan and lower taxes, too
I'm having an orgasm
Wait, there's more, I'll throw something in too
Interest
And compound interest
I can't take it!
How do private pension providers earn a living?
Look, it's Norbert Blüm!
Where?
Oh, he's gone
Your employer has your money for you
Is it time?
I'm going into retirement!
Happy birthday to...
Well, I find this
a bit small
It's much less than I paid!
That's a temporal illusion
Wait a minute, I'd like to see that in slow motion
Stop, stop!
Every month you're putting 20% in your own pocket!
That's stealing!
Those are provision charges
And what about the contributions you promised to pay?
That's an optional service
But you I heard it from your own tongue!
That's right,
a slip of the tongue
What about the guaranteed interest, how high is it?
Yes, that's around about...
percent or so
What?  I didn't catch that
Yeah, that's about
1.5%
1.5%?
That's not even enough for poverty!
It's still more than I have here
It's like someone else was also helping themseves
Wait, slow motion
Wait a minute
Frau Merkel
Hello
Frau Merkel you're in bed with Wopp
Pensions can't be tax free
But you said you'd subsidise the company pension scheme
The scheme, yes, but not the pension
You're stealing from a collection box
on your way out
The important thing is that everyone saw your donation
So, that's purely contentions
It's OK as long as everyone noticed your donation
But absolutely correct, yes
What's happening?
Well, these are welfare payments, health insurance
You need to pay these too
And partly those of your boss
It's not called a company pension scheme for nothing
This is total crap
The employer gets to put his hands in twice and I don't get anything!
I'd have been better off with the state pension
That's purely contentious
But absolutely correct
I have no future
with you
Future?  Oh please!
Who needs a future these days, right?
We have the great coalition
With that, you don't need a future anymore.
What do you we get from it?
A burnt-out CDU party, fading away in the glow
of a grey pant suit
teamed up with a completely depressed, disillusioned SPD
Feeding on the spit of their great leader, Sigmar Gabriel
Selling out every value they once had
And selling it to themselves as a success
That's where we're at
No more expectations
And they can't fulfill even these
And that is the difference to the Ukraine
That is the difference to the Ukraine, the people have already noticed it there
And when Egon Bahr stands up and says international politics
are never about human rights or democracy,
always about the interests of individual states
Then I'll say one thing to Herr Bahr
It's about the interests of those who have incorporated the state
Because before you export a democracy, you should have one yourself
And that doesn't look too good where we are, look
at the case of Edathy and Hans Peter Friedrich, I don't know if you remember him
He was our Internal Affairs Minister
He had to resign,
and this is the joke,
because he knew something
And then he stupidly kept talking and revealed state secrets
Democracy has now become a self-service shop
for industry and politics
Where anyone can take, with a feudal flourish,
anything out which suits him
That's not even taking Uli Hoeneß into the equation
That's how far we've come
At the top, we have a chancellor,
a political fat maggot
Now it's getting fierce, don't be scared
Who has now pumped herself into power
and lost all interest in what she could do with it
I'm not criticising the fact that she's chancellor, I just think she could
show more interest in politics
She gets everything from the media, like in the Edathy affair:
"I have just heard that in the media."
"And about Ukraine, I've just heard that in the media, too."
I think, that's comforting, at least she still
reads the paper
I've criticised governments for wanting the wrong thing
But now I have to admit, this government doesn't want anything at all
Although, a country-wide minimum wage, we were promised that, and what comes?
It's not coming yet, and it won't come everywhere
What if you said that to your wife, "Honey, I love you,
but not now and not always, but apart from that...
We get along well, right?"
And the really important issues are swept under the carpet
The No Spy Agreement, it gets swept under the carpet, fizzles out
And at the same time, in secret negotiations, the...
the biggest agreements, they're sealed in clandestine negotiations
Now American products are coming to supermarkets,
complete rubbish, by the way
In America, products are classed as foodstuffs
which are forbidden here in hardware stores
Then I feel sick, let's come back to the Ukraine,
that our government just accepts that a war is starting in Europe
that people will have to die for democracy and freedom
but really just for the interests of big corporations
I feel sick
And then I do think that the great coalition is the right one at the right time
Germany has won this crisis, we've read that everwhere
And that's why I think that they'll do anything to make sure
that this crisis happens again
We're heading in the right direction, and Frau Merkel
will have a good excuse at the end
She'll say, "I'm chancellor?
Unfortunately I've also just learnt that from the media."
Good evening
I've explained it a thousand times, the situation is clear,
we have a good state pension fund,
then the demographic lie,
pensions are cut,
everyone should look elsewhere, who gets the most out of this?
People like Wopp
The case is solved
Yes, it sounds completely plausible
But I still haven't understood
Then let's maybe put ourselves...
Let's reconstruct the crime, and put ourselves in the enemy's shoes
Who do you want to be?
We have the Deutsche Bank, the DWS
The Herold from the Deutsche Bank, Allianz Insurance
AXA, maybe, or Gothaer Insurance, Ergo Insurance, Victoria Insurance
or the AWD
All of them
That's what I thought, congratulations, Herr Uthoff,
you are private insurance
Let's imagine, 90s, beginning
Life insurance isn't doing too good
What do you do?
Well, I need a new product
- Yes!
- Private pension schemes
Good.  Just that the state pension system is so good that no one wants a private scheme
- Well, then I need to badmouth the system
- Yes
But you can't do that yourself
Then I'll take a few independant experts
Beautiful!
I'll give you, for example, Meinhard Migel and Kurt Biedenkopf
What am I supposed to do with those CDU clowns?
You turn them into the German Pension Experts
By founding an institute
The IWG in Bonn, the institute for economy and society
- IWG - I'll Win Gold
- Yes
Not quite yet
But we're close, now all you need to do is ensure the IWG
draws conclusions which benefit you
That won't be a problem, I'll shove so much money in the arses
that the right thing comes out the other end
You can't do it quite like that
Then I'll put an institute in the middle
Better
"German Institute for Retirement Planning", the DIA
Funded by
The Deutsche Bank,
the DWS, and Deutscher Herold
- So, by us
- Yes!
And what do they get out of it?
Yes, that get... wait a minute...
The state pension scheme is too expensive, and we need to insure privately
And that means here, here, here and here
I have to think of everyone
Very good!
But now it's like this:
The state pensions are still to high
Yes, and people like Norber Blüm don't want
to expose you completely
Pig
What do you do now?
- I'll go to his superior!
- Yes sir!
It's just that Kohl doesn't feel like changing anything, after 16 years in power
Then I need a new one
Ah, it's '98, people feel like a change, and who could...
- Gerhard Schröder
- Yes!
Wait, he has this pal, Maschmeyer
- He works for us, I know him, he'll handle everything
- Excellent
Carsten Maschmeyer from the AWD
Now you only have one problem:
Something is obstructing Schröder
Oh, his wife
No, Oskar Lafontaine
He doesn't like your private retirement plan at all
Pig
Remember you have Maschmayer
Then I go to him and say, "Maschy, Baby,
put it in every newspaper that the next chancellor must be from Niedersachsen."
Yes!  It works, Schröder becomes chancellor,
he gets rid of Lafontaine
And is very thankful to do everything you tell him to
But how can I be sure that really choose a private pension?
Um, like I said, you just have Schröder decrease pension payments
Private retirement schemes are subsidised, and then let's do something like
the Riester scheme
Ah, the oil reservoir
But we drill even deeper, Herr Uthoff
How about having Schröder found a committee of experts
And have a look if we don't need another pension reform
This committee could maybe be called Rürup
Then lets fill it with all manner of experts
Very good, I'll give you for example
Professor Bert Rürup
Wonderful, he's on the board of AXA and Gothaer Insurance
Very nice.  And he's the head of the Munich research institute for the economics of aging
- Which is completely funded by us
- Yes
I like how you think
- I also have Herr Raffelhüschen...
- He's... he's much more...
wage-dependent!  He works at Ergo, and at Victoria!
Lovely!  So, the Rürup Committee comes to the conclusion
that pensions need to go down 25%
What does Schröder do?
Lowers pensions by 25%
That means more profit for you
How nice
But I feel a bit guilty
You?
Look, these men have worked so hard
to castrate the state retirement system
Can't I have a little something come their way?
Millions in contract fees
But a million like that disappears so quickly
With such a measly pension at the end
Don't worry, look at this
Professor - civil servant, so pension
And here a lawyer, so law society, we spoke about that before
Politician, also pension, and here again, and again, and again
And this guy
has a rich wife
That means everyone
who has worked here to destroy the retirement system
aren't dependent on it
That's a scandal, that's crying out for revolution
To the barricades for a good state pension fund!
One that every one puts money into
Civil servants, politicians,
even you, Herr Uthoff
Why the Ukranian flag now?
That's not the Ukranian flag,
that's the flag of the German pension fund
Very nice
Pension murderer!
Is the guillotine ready?
The revolution kicks off
We still need a charismatic leader
Maybe someone who can meet the people on the street
at eye level
[It's Norbert Blüm]
I'll do it
Great!  Come!
A politician as a revolutionary leader
it'll be our ruin
So, for 20 years
I've had the pension system thrown in my face
And now I'm hitting back!
But first we need to question a few things
That's even worse than the guillotine!
Guillotine!
You cut off the legs off the pension system
And now you say it won't stand!
You said the pension scheme
was too expensive
You didn't notice, with the state system there would have been much more money
to pay the pensions
People said
the pension system wasn't effective
My God, the administration costs of the state pension system
are 1.5% of its takings
Private retirement schemes:
20% and more
And then there's all the pencil pushers
Advertising, dividends
I'll say one more thing
People said
State pensions weren't secure
More than 100 years
The state pension fund
survived every disaster, every crisis in the last century
Hyperinflation, two world wars
You can't say that
about private insurance
Their history is the history of
broken promises
That is the truth!
One question
Tell me, an old-school Marxist such as yourself,
could you tell us what's written on this banner?
It says
You did that on purpose
"The pension fund is secure"
That was the Institution
Occupied today by...